Didi Suhardi

+6285747345930 | didisuhardi00@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/didi-suhardi-7478bb228 | didisuhardi.github.io Semarang, Indonesia

SUMMARY

Fresh graduate of Computer Engineering at Diponegoro University. High-achieving person, detail-oriented and have various leadership and organization experience. Excel at leadership, project management, web development, embedded system with python and IT research. Have strong interest in technology especially in software and embedded system.

EDUCATION

Universitas Diponegoro

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Aug 2020 - Apr 2024

- CGPA 3.86/4.00
- Graduated Cum Laude

SMA N 1 Sukorejo

Mathematics and Natural Science (MIPA)

Jun 2017 - May 2020

SKILLS

Leadership, Project Management, English, Microsoft Office, Adobe Photoshop, UI design with Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Embedded System, SQL, Product Innovation, Data Analytic, Looker Studio, Agile & DevOps Essentials.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Core Initiative Studio

Project Based Intern: Frontend Developer

Aug 2023 - Sep 2023

- Completing various task related with the activity of frontend development from Core Initiative Studio, such as code
 with Vue.Js and Unit Testing with Jest
- Develop prototype for a single page website connected to API as a product catalog with Vue Js

Teknik Komputer Universitas Diponegoro

Practicum Coordinator of Advanced Digital System

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

- Led a team of 5 assistants and collaborate with the lecturers and lab coordinator to taught 167 students to use Nexys A7-100T FPGA Board with Verilog
- Create and implement practicum curriculum consist of 5 modules about coding structure, code reuse, coding with clocking-function, latches, and Finite State Machine
- Communicate, cooperate, and consult with lecturer and academy administration

Teknik Komputer Universitas Diponegoro

Front-End Web Developer for Computer Engineering Library Repository System

Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

- Developing prototype website for repository system utilizing Laravel framework
- Executed UI slicing and functional implementation for the frontend in responsive layout
- Performed front-end development using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Implementing AJAX autocomplete feature to enhance user interaction and search functionality

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

Forum Studi Teknik

Vice President

Nov 2022 - Nov 2023

- Support President to directed 109 members of Forum Studi Teknik
- Representing and taking over the duties of the President in case of absence and being accountable to President.
- Lead and collaborate with Research and Development Team to supervised and evaluate performance of 45 project from 6 Division and Internal Champion Team
- Improving the performance, kinship and quality control of the staff by implementing internal staff evaluation and assessment

Forum Studi Teknik

Secretary of Education Division

Jan 2022 - Nov 2022

- Support Head division to guided and managed 11 staff on improving English skill and engineering knowledge inside the organization.
- Performs a wide variety of clerical and secretarial work, including typing, filing, checking and recording information.
- Administered financial planning and management within the Education Division

Forum Studi Teknik

Staff of Education Division Mar 2021 – Jan 2022

• Head of Fundraising Division at EEC (English Engineering Competition), a competition to enhance English skill among engineering student at Faculty of Engineering, Diponegoro University

- Committee of Design, Decoration, and Documentation Division at FAST (FST Academic Super Training), an event to introduce FST and engineering information for Faculty of Engineering freshman student
- Committee of Event Division at EPIC 2 (English Preparation Class), an internal FST event about English Scientific Writing for Conference and Expo
- Master of Ceremony at BIBIT (Bincang-Bincang Teknik), a webinar and FGD session about Technologies to convert food waste into Electricity as a Source of Renewable Energy with Faculty of Engineering Students
- Secretary at EPIC 1 (English Preparation Class), an internal Forum Studi Teknik event about optimizing English usage at various media
- Elected to be Staff of The Year FST 2021 & Education Division Staff of The Month Mei's Edition

Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Komputer

Head of Research Division

Jul 2022 - Aug 2023

- Led a team of 6 research staff on providing a research development platform for Computer Engineering students
- Supervised all the work program hosted by Research Division

Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Komputer

Staff of Research and Technology

Jun 2021 – Jul 2022

- Person in charge of Info Lomba, a monthly issue about various competition that held in a month for Computer Engineering Students
- Head of Design, Decoration, and Documentation Division of School of Research (SOR 2021) at Computer Engineering Department
- Head of Event Division of PKM Center 2021 at Computer Engineering Department

Public Speaking Experience

•	Speaker of Computer Engineering School of Research (SOR) about "Introduction to Scientific Papers (KTI) and Techniques for Creating Research Proposals (PKM)" Part of the oration team for Orientasi Diponegoro Muda Fakultas Teknik (ODM FT) Undip 2023 about	Sep 2023
	"The values of Engineering students"	Aug 2023
•	Speaker of Computer Engineering Recreation 2022 about "Embedded System and IoT Introduction"	Oct 2022
Honor & Awards		
•	Top 10th Best Participant of Future Me (Mandirian Excellence) by PT Bank Mandiri (Persero) Tbk	2024
•	Awardee of My Digital Academy Batch 2 by PT Bank Mandiri (Persero) Tbk	2023
•	Awardee of UNESCO Youth as Researchers and Tanoto Student Research Awards (YAR-TSRA)	2023
•	Scholarship Awardee of Bakti BCA Scholarship	2022
•	Bronze Medalist of Tanoto Student Research Award	2022
•	Staff of The Year Forum Studi Teknik	2021
•	2 nd Place of PKM-KC PIM Undip by Universitas Diponegoro	2021
•	Best Paper Essay of Champion Award by Forum Studi Teknik	2021
•	Best Participant of Research Champion Academy by Forum Studi Teknik	2021